

#### SHAZIL MUHAMMED SHAFEEK

#### **Linux Administrator**

Marathahalli, Bangalore Mobile - +919562066323, +917012020522

Email - shaazilmohd@gmail.com Skype ID - shazilmohd

## **Profile**

Three plus years of experience in Linux System Administration, IT Support and Network Administration specialising in the planning, deployment, monitoring, and support of IT hardware and software. Strong information technology professional with a Bachelor's Degree focused in Computer Science and Engineering from University of Calicut.

## **Skills**

- Linux
- Docker
- Apache
- Nginx
- Ansible
- Cisco Catalyst Switches
- Cyberoam Firewall
- Puppet
- Jenkins
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- Windows
- Mac
- IBM AIX
- Phabricator

## Qualification

- B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering (MES College of Engineering, Kuttipuram)
- PLUS TWO (IPC HSS, Maniyur)
- SSLC (Govt. THSS, Thiruvangoor)

# **Professional Experience**

Systems Engineer, IT Operations
 QBurst Technologies (Nov, 2015 - Jan, 2018)



Linux Administrator
 IBM India pvt ltd (June 2019 - June 2020)



System Administrator
 Intel Technologies (Dec, 2020 - Present)



# **Technical Expertize**

- Web Servers Apache, Nginx
- Operating Systems Ubuntu, Centos, Debian, Redhat, Windows, Cisco IOS, Mac, IBM AIX
- Switches Cisco SG300-52P, Cisco SG300-28P, Cisco SG300-28P PoE
- Firewall Cyberoam CR200Ing, IPtables
- Wireless Routers Aruba IAP-205, D-Link, Belkin
- Linux fundamentals
- Docker application deployment with containers
- Basic knowledge in Puppet and Ansible
- Basic knowledge in AWS services.
- Basic knowledge in database administration on MySQL and PostgreSQL

# **Roles and Responsibilities**

Intel Technologies:

- Install and configure Docker
- Use Ansible for package installations on client devices.
- Install and configure Ubuntu, Centos, Windows based on the development requirements.
- Install and configure CPU, NIC cards on Supermicro, intel and dell servers.
- Configure proxy for Lab network devices.
- Coordinate with IT Support team for Lab network Infrastructure requirements.

- Redmine
- Bugzilla
- DHCP
- Service now
- Shell Scripting
- Nagios
- Proxmox
- Proxy
- IT Asset Management
- Hardware Support
- VPN
- IT Infrastructure management

# **Key Strengths and Personal Qualities**

- Ability to assess problems and research solutions
- Flexibility
- Responsiveness
- Proactive
- Time management
- Interactive and a team player

### **Personal Information**

- Date of Birth: 29th October 1991
- Sex & Status: Male & Single
- Nationality: INDIAN
- Languages Known: English, Malayalam, Tamil and Hindi

## Linkedin

www.linkedin.com/in/shazilmuhamme d-shafeek

#### Website

www.shaazil.online

- Manage KVM devices.
- Provide support for network connectivity and RDP issues
- Install add on PCI cards as per the requirement.
- Configure console IP and login for Supermicro, Intel and Dell servers.
- Install Hard disks, RAM for NUC, tank, Boxer, Flex and Desktop devices.

## IBM India pvt ltd:

- Monitoring the Customer Servers, Applications and environment.
- Performing first level problem determinations.
- Perform health checks on servers, monitoring backups and rerun if failed.
- Execute Scripts as per the schedule and manage time dependent and task dependent scripts.
- Attend Daily service reviews, change approval and walkthrough calls.
- Perform L1 troubleshooting, engage concerned teams and drive incidents to resolutions.

#### **QBurst Technologies**:

- Deploy and manage Docker containers.
- Manage AWS EC2 instances.
- Cyberoam Firewall management.
- Provide support for configuring Apache and Nginx web servers.
- Database administration on Mysql and PostgreSQL.
- Installation and maintenance of Linux, Windows and Mac based systems within a client's digital environment.
- Resolve tickets in WebHost Manager Complete Solution (WHMCS).
- Provide Support for Hostingsource customer on Linux and Windows server issues.
- Provide support for tools like Cpanel/WHM, WordPress, Virtualizor.
- Administration of Antivirus Server and Clients by using Symantec Endpoint Protection.
- Monitoring bandwidth usage and maintain reports.
- Provide Hardware support.
- Provide day to day support for internal network/WAN infrastructure and connectivity requirements.
- Configure Cyberoam firewall PPTP, IPSEC, L2TP, SSL VPNs

#### Reference

- Arun S Raj (arunraj@qburst.com)
   Lead System Engineer, IT
   Operations (QBurst Technologies)
   Mob: 9995333287
- Sabeesh Thomas
   (sabeesh@qburst.com)
   Associate Manager, IT Operations
   (QBurst Technologies)
   Mob: 9535712352
- Puneet Kittur (puneet\_kittur@in.ibm.com)Delivery Operations Manager, IBM

Mob: 9611127003

Rashmi M A
 (rashmi.m.a@intel.com)

 Program Manager
 Mob: 9902016851

- Evaluates industry trends, standards and new technologies (i.e., to evaluate and integrate new OS versions, Drivers and Hardware).
- Secure Internet access for end-users by installing and maintaining Aruba centralized wireless architecture with single point or access control.
- Provide support for backup/recovery and disaster recovery solutions.
- Designed and deployed company LANs, WANs, and wireless networks, including servers, routers, switches, and hardwares.

## **Achievements**

- Configure Docker Server and local repository for development team.
- Configured Phabricator, Bugzilla and Redmine bug tracking tools.
- Configured Cyberoam Firewall for more than 200 client devices.

# **Professional Training**

- RHCE (Red Hat Certified Engineer)
- CCNA (Cisco Certified Network Associate)
- MCSA (Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate)

#### **Declaration**

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true and complete to the best of my knowledge and belief.

SHAZIL MUHAMMED SHAFEEK